<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Keto Enthusiast, Indian Food Lover</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 09:29:21 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 09:29:21 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vegan Keto Breads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2879/33512455012_3a94b9c20b_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Making low carb bread can be a real challenge for vegans, as most keto breads are heavily egg based. I am afraid I found very few options for vegan keto breads, but I have tried most of the ones in this roundup and they will not let you down! &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
If you are a fan of indian food, you will love to hear you can make roti out of &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/coconutRoti&quot;&gt;coconut flour&lt;/a&gt;, out of &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/flaxRoti&quot;&gt;ground flax&lt;/a&gt;, and you can even try to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dietdoctor.com/recipes/low-carb-naan-bread-with-melted-garlic-butter&quot;&gt;naan with coconut flour&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;50%&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/611/31098451014_a30e85f82a_o_d.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
These &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/broccoliParatha&quot;&gt;broccoli parathas&lt;/a&gt; are delicious and require very few ingredients; simply substitute the cream cheese for your favorite almond cheese and you are in business!
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;50%&quot; src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/33142336950_46222c202f_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
For bread buns, you can enjoy these &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/almondBread&quot;&gt;almond buns&lt;/a&gt; which are amazing for your morning toast!
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;50%&quot; src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2718/32865236166_44a912cebe_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
If you miss crunchyness in your keto life, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lowcarb-vegan.net/easy-flax-crackers/&quot;&gt;these crackers&lt;/a&gt; will save your day, and would make an awesome appetizer for your next low carb party. 
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;50%&quot; src=&quot;https://lowcarb-vegan.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/IMG_5934-770x579.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
And last but not least – the next recipes are probably the most bread-like, BUT they use vital wheat gluten, which might be a problem for some. I however sometimes use gluten for sausages or for bread and have no problem with it, so I thought I would include these as well: this recipe makes for an amazing looking &lt;a href=&quot;https://lowcarb-vegan.net/real-bread-low-carb-vegan-style/&quot;&gt;bread loaf&lt;/a&gt; (and is very similar to a recipe that I myself make and that I love!), you can make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://lowcarb-vegan.net/delicious-low-carb-vegan-nutty-bread/&quot;&gt;nutty bread&lt;/a&gt; and you can even make her &lt;a href=&quot;https://lowcarb-vegan.net/low-carb-vegan-focaccia/&quot;&gt;low-carb foccacia&lt;/a&gt;! Hats off to Martine for these, they look absolutely delicious!
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;50%&quot; src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2878/32853938723_0eb21aa28c_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/veganBreads</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/veganBreads</guid>
        
        <category>bread</category>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pan ceto (soul bread)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2945/33412933702_4fd9defc19_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Soul bread” es un pan elaborado con proteina de suero de leche (whey) y es muy popular para quienes siguen una dieta cetogenica o baja en hidratos y echen de menos los sandwiches o tostadas. Esta es mi version, que resulta en un pan esponjoso, suave y un poquito dulce, genial para hacer un sandwich mixto! Con estas cantidades las rebanadas no son muy grandes, asi que si quieres puedes doblar la receta y usar el mismo molde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cucharadas colmadas de queso de untar (180 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80 g de proteina de suero de leche (whey protein) sabor neutro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup (27 g) aceite de oliva&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup (31 g) de yogur griego&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup (30 g) de nata de montar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 huevos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cdita vinagre de manzana&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cdita bicarbonato&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cdita sal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 y 1/4 cdita de polvo de psyllium (3 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elaboracion&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 180C.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend the eggs, yogurt, cream, oil, vinegar and cream cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mix the whey protein, salt, baking powder and psyllium husk powder.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add the dry ingredients into the wet ones and mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pour onto a greased breadloaf pan (if you prefer, you can put some parchment paper on the inside of the pan instead of greasing it).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bake at 180C for 45-50 minutes or until a toothpick inserted in the middle comes out clean. If it starts getting too golden on the top, cover with aluminum foil to avoid it burning.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wait until it is completely cooled down to slice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informacion nutricional&lt;/strong&gt;, por rebanada (hace 16 rebanadas)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;79.5 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.65 g H de C netos&lt;/strong&gt;, 0.15 g fibra, 0.8 g H de C totales&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6.4 g grasa&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6.4 g proteina&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/soulBreadSpa</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/soulBreadSpa</guid>
        
        <category>vegetariano</category>
        
        <category>bajo en hidratos</category>
        
        <category>huevos</category>
        
        
        <category>pan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keto Bread (soul bread)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2945/33412933702_4fd9defc19_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soul bread is a very popular option for ketoers who miss sandwiches and toast. This is my take at it, which results in a spongy, soft, slightly sweet bread, amazing for grilled cheese! With these amounts you will get pieces of bread on the smaller side, so if you want bigger slices, just double all the ingredients and use the same breadloaf pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 heaping tablespoons of cream cheese (180 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80 g unflavored whey protein&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup olive oil (27 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup of greek yogurt (31 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup heavy whipping cream (30 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp apple cider vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 and 1/4 tsp psyllium husk powder (3 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 180C.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend the eggs, yogurt, cream, oil, vinegar and cream cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mix the whey protein, salt, baking powder and psyllium husk powder.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add the dry ingredients into the wet ones and mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pour onto a greased breadloaf pan (if you prefer, you can put some parchment paper on the inside of the pan instead of greasing it).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bake at 180C for 45-50 minutes or until a toothpick inserted in the middle comes out clean. If it starts getting too golden on the top, cover with aluminum foil to avoid it burning.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wait until it is completely cooled down to slice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutritional information&lt;/strong&gt;, per slice (makes 16 slices)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;79.5 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.65 g net carbs&lt;/strong&gt;, 0.15 g fiber, 0.8 g total carbs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6.4 g fat&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6.4 g protein&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/soulBread</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/soulBread</guid>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>low-carb</category>
        
        <category>eggs</category>
        
        
        <category>bread</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Momo (ravioli Tibet) ceto</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2910/33412902552_247165440c_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Para aquellos que echen de menos las gyozas, momo, etc… esta es tu receta!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Los momos son una especie de raviolis hechos al vapor tipicos de Tibet y Nepal, muy populares como snack en India. La receta tradicional se hace con harina de trigo y se sirve con salsa picante; de hecho, la tengo publicada en uno de mis posts antiguos, de cuando comia bajo en grasa y alto en hidratos…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asi que ahora he logrado hacer una nueva, mejorada version, baja en hidratos! El relleno es de pollo, mantequilla y calabacin; la verdura le da un poco de humedad, pero la puedes suprimir e incrementar el pollo y mantequilla para que sea aun mas ceto. La masa es de semillas de sesamo, psilio y harina de coco (puedes usar todo harina de coco siguiendo mi receta de &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/tortillaCoco&quot;&gt;rotis de harina de coco&lt;/a&gt; pero yo no queria momos con sabor a coco). Estuve a punto de no subir esta receta porque los momos me salieron morados… pero he leido que esto es por el psilio y que depende de la marca. Y aunque salgan morados, estos momos estan riquisimos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;75 g de pollo picado&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 g de calabacín rallado&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cucharada (15 g) mantequilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cdita de comino molido&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cdita de cilantro molido&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opcional: 1/8 cdita de fenugreco molido&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opcional: pizca de chili en polvo al gusto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/8 cdita Jengibre en polvo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/8 cdita ajo en polvo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cdita cebolla en polvo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cda de salsa soja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cdas ajetes tiernos picados (10 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;55 g sésamo molido&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cditas de aceite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3,5 cdas de psilio molido (28 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/8 taza (15 g) harina de coco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elaboración&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mezcla los ingredientes para el relleno: calabacin, pollo, mantequilla, especias, salsa soja y 1/8 cdita de sal. Si quieres comprobar el punto de sal, coge un trocito pequeño de masa, cocínalo a la plancha y pruébalo.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mezcla el sésamo molido, psilio en polvo, harina de coco y 1/4 cdita de sal. Después añade el aceite y el agua, empezando con 1/4 de taza y echando más poco a poco hasta tener una masa maleable.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Toma un trozo de masa de tamaño algo más pequeño que una bola de golf. Con un rodillo, forma un rodillo de 2-3 mm de grosor; puedes humedecer la masa un poco si está seca, para que se forme mejor.. Con un cuchillo, recorta los bordes para tener un disco de unos 10 cm de diámetro.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Echa una cucharadita de relleno en el centro y después forma el momo como se ve en el video.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Una vez hayas formado todos los momos, cocínalos al vapor durante unos 10 minutos o hasta que el pollo esté bien cocinado.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sírvelo con un chutney picante, como &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/acharSpa&quot;&gt;este&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Información nutricional&lt;/strong&gt;, por momo (si haces 10 momo)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;66 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 g H de C netos&lt;/strong&gt;, 3 g fibra, 4.1 g H de C totales&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2.8 g proteina&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;5.3 g grasa&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/momoCeto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/momoCeto</guid>
        
        <category>indio</category>
        
        <category>bajo en hidratos</category>
        
        <category>pollo</category>
        
        
        <category>aperitivo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keto Chicken Momo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2910/33412902552_247165440c_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For those who miss dumplings… this is your recipe!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Momos are steamed dumplings made in Tibet and Nepal, and very popular as a snack in India. They are usually made with a white flour dough and served with very spicy sauce; I actually have the traditional recipe in one of my oldest posts, from back when I ate low fat high carb…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I decided to make a new, improved, low carb version! The filling is made with chicken, buttter and zucchini; I like the zucchini to add some extra moisture, but you can leave it out and increase the chicken and butter to make an even more keto version. The dough is made mixing ground sesame seeds, psyllium husk and coconut flour (you can use all coconut flour following the recipe for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/coconutRoti&quot;&gt;coconut flour roti&lt;/a&gt; but I didn’t want my momo to taste like coconut!). I almost didn’t upload these because they turned out purple… but I read that this can be caused by the psyllium husk and it can depend on the brand. And even if they come out purple, these are delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;75 g minced chicken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 g shredded zucchini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp(15 g) butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp ground coriander&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: 1/8 tsp ground fenugreek (methi)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: pinch of chili to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp ground ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp ground garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp ground onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp chopped scallions (10 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;55 g ground sesame seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3,5 tbsp psyllium husk powder (28 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 cup (15 g) coconut flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mix the ingredients for the filling: chicken, butter, zucchini, spices, soy sauce and 1/8 tsp salt. If you want to check for salt, take a small amount of the filling and cook in a pan, then taste it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mix the ground sesame, psyllium husk powder, coconut flour and 1/4 tsp salt. Then add the oil and water, starting with 1/4 cup of water and adding more little by little until you have a dough you can shape.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Take a piece of dough slightly smaller than a goldball. With a rolling pin, roll it to 2-3 mm thick; you can add a bit of water if the dough is dry and crumbling. Then trim the edges to make a 10 cm diameter disk.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Put a teaspoon of filling in the centre and then form the momo as seen in the video.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Once all the momos are formed, steam them for about 10 minutes or until the chicken is cooked inside.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Serve with spicy chutney, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://maria.recipes/acharEng&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutritional information&lt;/strong&gt;, per momo (if making 10 momo)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;66 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 g net carbs&lt;/strong&gt;, 3 g fiber, 4.1 g total carbs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2.8 g protein&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;5.3 g fat&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/ketoMomo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/ketoMomo</guid>
        
        <category>indian</category>
        
        <category>low-carb</category>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        
        <category>snack</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paratha queso-brocoli</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/33142336950_46222c202f_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una receta simple con solo 5 ingredientes para preparar parathas de brocoli rellenos de queso de untar. Son deliciosos para desayunar con una salsa india (pickle), y si eres vegano puedes usar la misma receta empleando queso de untar de almendra en lugar de queso de leche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 manojo de brocoli (250 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3,5 tbsp polvo de psyllium (28 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Un buen pellizco de sal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 tbsp (120g) de queso de untar (lo puedes sustituir por paneer si quieres)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cucharaditas de ghee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Especias al gusto (opcional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elaboracion&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cocina el brocoli (hirviendolo o al vapor) hasta que se pueda pinchar con un tenedor, sin sobrecocinar para que no pierda el color.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Batelo con 2 cucharadas de agua.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Agrega el psyllium y sal al pure de brocoli, junto a las especias que quieras (ajo y cebolla en polvo irian genial) y mezcla hasta tener una masa.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Divide la masa en 8 partes iguales.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Utilizando un rodillo o un chakla (yo cubro la superficie con film transparente para que no se pegue, mojando un poco la superficie antes para que luego el film no se mueva), forma un disco de aproximadamente 1 mm de grosor con cada trozo de masa.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Coge un disco, extiende dos cucharadas de queso por encima, pon otro disco encima y cierra los bordes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Derrite 1 cucharadita de ghee en una sarten antiadherente a fuego medio-alto. Cocina el paratha unos 3-4 minutos por el primer lado hasta que este dorado, luego cocina el otro lado otros 2-3 minutos.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cocina los cuatro parathas de esta manera y sirvelos con una salsa baja en hidratos.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informacion nutricional&lt;/strong&gt;, por paratha (la receta es para 4 parathas)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;144 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.2 g H de C netos&lt;/strong&gt;, 6.8 g fibra, 11.1 g H de C totales&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;13.7 g grasa&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;4.2 g proteina&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/parathaBrocoli</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/parathaBrocoli</guid>
        
        <category>vegano</category>
        
        <category>vegetariano</category>
        
        <category>bajo en hidratos</category>
        
        <category>indio</category>
        
        
        <category>pan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Broccoli Cheese Paratha</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/33142336950_46222c202f_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple, 5 ingredient recipe to make broccoli parathas stuffed with cream cheese. They are amazing with some pickle for breakfast! And if you are vegan, you can use some almond cream cheese instead of regular cream cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 bunch of broccoli (250 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3,5 tbsp psyllium husk powder (28 g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A big pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 tbsp (120g) cream cheese (you can substitute for paneer if you want)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tsp ghee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spices to taste (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cook the broccoli (boil or steam) until fork tender, without overcooking so it doesnt lose the green color.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend the broccoli with 2 tbsp water.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add the psyllium husk and salt to the broccoli puree, along with other spices if you want (some garlic powder and onion powder could be great!) and mix until you have a dough.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Divide the dough into 8 equal parts.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using a chakla or a rolling pin (i like to cover my surface with plastic wrap to avoid any stickiness - by putting a bit of water on the surface first, the plastic wrap won’t move when you roll), roll each part into a very thin disk of about 1 mm thickness.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Take a disk, spread 2 tbsp cheese on it, then put another disk on top. Pinch the edges to seal.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Melt 1 tsp of ghee on a non stick pan over medium high heat. Cook the paratha for 3-4 minutes on one side until it is brown, then filp and cook further 2-3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cook all four parathas this way and serve with a low carb pickle.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutritional information&lt;/strong&gt;, per paratha (recipe makes 4)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;144 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.2 g net carbs&lt;/strong&gt;, 6.8 g fiber, 11.1 g total carbs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;13.7 g fat&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;4.2 g protein&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/broccoliParatha</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/broccoliParatha</guid>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>low-carb</category>
        
        <category>indian</category>
        
        
        <category>bread</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pimientos rellenos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/427/33000011456_d72a752d26_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Una receta sencilla para pimientos rellenos de carne picada, que puedes variar incluyendo las especias que mas te gusten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 pimientos verdes grandes o bien 6 pimientos verdes italianos (500g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400 g carne de ternera picada (20% grasa)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50 g cebolla (1/2 mediana)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 dientes de ajo muy finamente picado&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sal, Pimienta negra molida, nuez moscada&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cdas aceite de oliva virgen extra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 huevo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perejil fresco&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 taza de tomate triturado o bien un tomate grande (180g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;60 mL de vino blanco o bien la mitad de vino blanco y la otra mitad de jerez o similar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elaboracion&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mezcla todos los ingredientes del relleno y metelo en el frigo al menos 30 minutos: carne, huevo, sal, pimienta, nuez moscada, perejil, ajo y el vino que prefieras.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Precalienta el horno a 200C.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Abre los pimientos quitando solo la parte superior (como si fuese una tapa) y vacialos por dentro.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Usa la mezcla de carne picada para rellenar los pimientos.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bate (o pica finamente) el tomate y la cebolla (puedes freir la cebolla usando la mitad del aceite de la receta) y viertelo por encima de los pimientos. Luego echa lo que quede de aceite y de vino blanco.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hornea durante 40 minutos o hasta que el pimiento quede blando y la carne hecha.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informacion nutricional&lt;/strong&gt;, por racion (sirve 3)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;110 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.6 g H de C netos&lt;/strong&gt;, 3.8 g fibra, 12.4 g H de C totales&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;27 g proteina&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;37.5 g grasa&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/pimientosRellenos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pimientosRellenos</guid>
        
        <category>bajo en hidratos</category>
        
        <category>carne</category>
        
        
        <category>principal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stuffed Green Peppers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/427/33000011456_d72a752d26_o_d.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple recipe for meat stuffed green peppers, that you can adapt to your taste by using different spices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 green bell peppers, big, or 6 small green peppers (500g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400 g minced beef (20% fat)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50 g onion (1/2 medium)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 garlic cloves very finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt, black pepper, nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fresh parsley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of tomato puree or one big tomato (180g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;60 mL white wine, or half white wine and half cherry or similar wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mix all the ingredients for the filling and keep in the fridge for at least 30 min: meat, egg, salt, pepper, nutmeg, parsley, garlic and white or cherry wine.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 200C.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open the peppers on the top (creating a lid) and throw away the seeds inside.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use the meat mixture to fill the peppers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend (or finely chop) the tomato and onion (you can use half the oil in the recipe to fry the onion) and pour over the peppers. Then add the remaining oil and white wine.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bake for about 40 minutes or until the pepper is tender and the meat is cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutritional information&lt;/strong&gt;, per serving (serves 3)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;110 kCal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.6 g net carbs&lt;/strong&gt;, 3.8 g fiber, 12.4 g total carbs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;27 g protein&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;37.5 g fat&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/stuffedPeppers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/stuffedPeppers</guid>
        
        <category>low-carb</category>
        
        <category>meat</category>
        
        
        <category>main</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paneer Makhani</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d30b2uadky41tr.cloudfront.net/Blog/image.axd?picture=/2017/02/PaneerMakhani1.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of my all-time favorite Paneer recipes, and I am so happy to have used it as my guest post at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ketodietapp.com&quot;&gt;the KetoDietApp website&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out the ingredients, instructions and nutritional information for this wonder of indian cuisine, just &lt;a href=&quot;https://ketodietapp.com/Blog/post/2017/02/21/low-carb-paneer-makhani&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/paneerMakhani</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/paneerMakhani</guid>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>indian</category>
        
        <category>curry</category>
        
        <category>low-carb</category>
        
        
        <category>main</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
